<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>翻译 - Category - 叶落风随</title>
        <link>https://lwyer.github.io/categories/%E7%BF%BB%E8%AF%91/</link>
        <description>翻译 - Category - 叶落风随</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><managingEditor>laiweiye@outlook.com (lwyer)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>laiweiye@outlook.com (lwyer)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 19:03:27 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lwyer.github.io/categories/%E7%BF%BB%E8%AF%91/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Closing a stale SSH connection关闭一个失效的SSH链接 | 翻译</title>
    <link>https://lwyer.github.io/%E7%BF%BB%E8%AF%91-%E5%85%B3%E9%97%AD%E4%B8%80%E4%B8%AA%E5%A4%B1%E6%95%88%E7%9A%84ssh%E9%93%BE%E6%8E%A5/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 19:03:27 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>lwyer</author>
    <guid>https://lwyer.github.io/%E7%BF%BB%E8%AF%91-%E5%85%B3%E9%97%AD%E4%B8%80%E4%B8%AA%E5%A4%B1%E6%95%88%E7%9A%84ssh%E9%93%BE%E6%8E%A5/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Suppose you’re connected to a remote host with SSH and after a while the SSH session goes stale. The terminal is unresponsive and no keypress seem to take effect. There might be something with the network, the remote host is restarting or maybe your machine has been in hibernation, there could be multiple reasons for a stale session.
假设你用SSH连接到一个远程主机，然后过一会儿SSH会话失效了。终端没有反应，而且似乎没有按键有效。可能是你的网络出了问题，远程主机正在重启或者也许是你的机器处于休眠状态，有多种原因可能使一个会话失效。
The first solution that might come to mind is to just close the terminal emulator and create another one, but there is a better way.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The difference between time and attention（时间和注意力的区别）| 翻译</title>
    <link>https://lwyer.github.io/%E7%BF%BB%E8%AF%91-%E6%97%B6%E9%97%B4%E5%92%8C%E6%B3%A8%E6%84%8F%E5%8A%9B%E7%9A%84%E5%8C%BA%E5%88%AB/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 15:27:09 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>jason fried</author>
    <guid>https://lwyer.github.io/%E7%BF%BB%E8%AF%91-%E6%97%B6%E9%97%B4%E5%92%8C%E6%B3%A8%E6%84%8F%E5%8A%9B%E7%9A%84%E5%8C%BA%E5%88%AB/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[A few years ago I realized that if I’m too busy to take something on, I shouldn’t say “I don’t have the time”. In fact, I often do have the time. It’s not that hard to squeeze in some extra time for someone.
几年前我意识到，如果我太忙没法做某些事情，我不应该说“我没有时间”。事实上，我经常有这个时间，为某些人挤出一些额外的时间并不难。
What I don’t have – and what I can’t squeeze in – is more attention. Attention is a far more limited resource than time. So what I should say is “I don’t have the attention”.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Why Prompt Engineering Is Nonsense 为什么（计算机上的）提示工程是没有意义的 | 翻译</title>
    <link>https://lwyer.github.io/%E7%BF%BB%E8%AF%91-%E4%B8%BA%E4%BB%80%E4%B9%88%E6%8F%90%E7%A4%BA%E5%B7%A5%E7%A8%8B%E5%B8%88%E6%98%AF%E6%B2%A1%E6%9C%89%E6%84%8F%E4%B9%89%E7%9A%84/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 19:57:18 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>pavkam</author>
    <guid>https://lwyer.github.io/%E7%BF%BB%E8%AF%91-%E4%B8%BA%E4%BB%80%E4%B9%88%E6%8F%90%E7%A4%BA%E5%B7%A5%E7%A8%8B%E5%B8%88%E6%98%AF%E6%B2%A1%E6%9C%89%E6%84%8F%E4%B9%89%E7%9A%84/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Like most people in tech, I have been bombarded lately with a ton of “AI stuff”. Articles upon articles of opinions and rants. Papers and videos on various subjects from technical architectures to societal impacts and beyond.
像大多数科技界人士一样，我最近被大量“AI的东西 ”所轰炸。（有）一篇又一篇的带有各种观点和争论的文章，（也有）从技术架构到社会影响等各种主题的论文和视频。
While one must preserve a level-headed view on all these subjects and opinions, two related topics make me sad and annoyed at the same time. Namely:
虽然一个人需要对各种主题和观点保持冷静，但有两个相关的话题让我同时感觉难过和恼火，即：
AI won’t replace people. People using AI will replace people, and, Prompt engineering is the future.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>You&#39;re not uncool. Making friends as an adult is just hard(不是你的问题，成年后交朋友太难了) | 翻译</title>
    <link>https://lwyer.github.io/%E7%BF%BB%E8%AF%91-%E6%88%90%E5%B9%B4%E5%90%8E%E4%BA%A4%E6%9C%8B%E5%8F%8B%E5%A4%AA%E9%9A%BE%E4%BA%86/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 13:25:21 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>wbur</author>
    <guid>https://lwyer.github.io/%E7%BF%BB%E8%AF%91-%E6%88%90%E5%B9%B4%E5%90%8E%E4%BA%A4%E6%9C%8B%E5%8F%8B%E5%A4%AA%E9%9A%BE%E4%BA%86/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[When you were a kid, it seemed like you could walk up to just about anybody and be best friends the next minute. But somewhere along the long, winding road to adulthood, making new friends became an impossibly hard thing to do.
当你还是一个孩子时，似乎你可以走到任何人身边，并在下一分钟成为最好的朋友。但在通往成年之路的漫长曲折的某个地方，交新朋友变成了一件不可能的事情。
Well according to psychologist and University of Maryland professor Marisa G. Franco, that’s because as you get older, making friends no longer happens organically.
好吧，根据Maryland大学的教授，心理学家Marisa G. Franco所说，这是因为当你长大后，交朋友不再自然而然地发生。]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Town(家乡) | 翻译</title>
    <link>https://lwyer.github.io/%E7%BF%BB%E8%AF%91-%E5%AE%B6%E4%B9%A1/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 15:22:17 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>rohit kumar</author>
    <guid>https://lwyer.github.io/%E7%BF%BB%E8%AF%91-%E5%AE%B6%E4%B9%A1/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I recently shifted from my home town to Delhi – the country&rsquo;s capital. When I was in my town, I missed Delhi. When I am in Delhi now, I miss my home town.
最近我离开家乡来到德里——国家的首都。当我在我的家乡时，我想去德里，可当我真正在德里时，我想念我的家乡。
You ask why?
Why I wanted to move to Delhi is a story for another day. But I will tell you why I desire to move back to my small and still home town.
你问我为什么？
我为什么想去德里改天再说吧，但是我想告诉你的是我为什么想从德里回到我那小小的平静的家乡。]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
